## Othneil Drew

## **Full Stack Developer**

Cypress, TX 77433 othneild@gmail.com (832) 942-8667

UI/UX pro with 6+ years of diverse leadership and management experience ready to put to use.

Massive appetite for learning. Dedicated to solving problems that improve the quality of life for others.

View My Portfolio: https://www.othneildrew.com

What community leaders are saying:

"Drew continues to astound me with how quickly he can learn and apply new skills." - Captain Roscoe Edwards (University Program Director)

"[Othneil] can be depended upon at a moment's notice... very efficient with managing his time between community affairs, his

education, work, and hobbies. I eagerly recommend [him] for any endeavor that he pursues..." - Cenita Heywood (Manager)

"Othneil is extremely creative and technologically savvy. He enjoys learning..." - R. Yancy (Professor)

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### Work Experience

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Snaju LLC - Houston, TX June 2019 to Present

- Experience with ITAR and 508 web accessibility compliance
- Lead discussions and client discovery meetings to establish clients' needs and determine what actions are required to reach their goals
- Determine technology stack to be used on a per-project basis
- Review and approve UI/UX designs and illustrations
- Implement new features using Agile/Scrum methodology
- · Interact with various front-end and back-end technology during each project
- Developed avionics simulator software for visualizing flights from aircraft flight data recorder in X-Plane
- Contribute to open source community and internal projects

#### **Founder & Software Engineer**

Student Pilot Portal - Houston, TX May 2015 to Present

- Long-term personal project to bring an e-learning platform where student pilots can learn to fly online
- Based on React|S and microservice architecture
- Design and implement user journeys for most optimal user experiences

- Convert PSD to responsive web layouts using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Resolve bugs through debugging and cross-browser compatibility testing
- · Apply Git version control software to track, test, and update the pre-existing codebase
- Create compelling and effective marketing content for social media campaigns
- Plan and implement architecture for MySQL relational databases and interface with various REST APIs

#### **IT Support Specialist**

Texas Southern University - Houston, TX February 2015 to Present

- Programing & configuring scenario-based training lessons according to strict Federal Aviation Administrator (FAA) regulations
- Assist with updating the department's WordPress website
- Take photos, videos, and produce other media to use for marketing on social media
- Constructing technical guides to educate faculty on air traffic control lab use
- Ensuring the correct usage and security of \$167,044 of flight simulation equipment
- Supervising pilot briefing room, including providing technical support to flight instructors and pilots
- Lead tours as a tour guide to visitors like high schools students, nonprofits, and other members of the community

## **Freelance Photographer**

Isiah Drew Photos - Houston, TX July 2014 to Present

Isiah Drew Photos is a professional photography company that I founded to work with online retailers like Amazon, eBay, Alibaba, etc. from around the world to bring product marketing and sales strategy through beautiful professional product photography at an affordable price. At the time, I specialized in product photography of electronics, clothing, models, hardware, and food accessories.

#### Education

#### **B.S. in Aviation Science Management**

Texas Southern University - Houston, TX August 2014 to Present

#### Front End Development in Computer Science

**Udemy Academy** 

Present

## **Responsive Web Design Developer in Computer Science**

freeCodeCamp

Present

#### Full Stack JavaScript Techdegree in Computer Science

Treehouse

Present

### Skills

• Javascript (6 years)

- HTML 5 (6 years)
- Laravel (4 years)
- MySQL (6 years)
- JQuery (4 years)
- PHP (6 years)
- Git (3 years)
- Bootstrap (4 years)
- GIMP (4 years)
- Agile Web Development (2 years)
- Bitbucket (2 years)
- Web Development (4 years)
- React (4 years)
- Front-End (6 years)
- UI (4 years)
- Front End (6 years)
- HTML5 (6 years)
- User Interface (6 years)
- SQL (6 years)
- CSS (6 years)
- GitHub (6 years)
- Node.js (4 years)
- XML (6 years)
- AJAX (6 years)
- REST (6 years)
- Scrum
- Web Services
- APIs
- SCSS
- SDLC
- SDKs
- Web accessibility
- Microservices
- JSON
- Application development

## Languages

• English - Expert

#### Links

https://github.com/othneildrew

https://linkedin.com/in/othneildrew

https://www.othneildrew.com

#### Awards

## Scholarship, Leadership and Service Award

February 2015

Awarded by the National Society of Collegiate Scholars in honor of commitment to the ideals of scholarship, leadership and service.

## Photographer's Forum Magazine - Award of Excellence

May 2014

Awarded by Photographer's Forum Magazine for Excellence in the 35th Annual College & High School Photography Contest.

# United Parcel Service Aerospace Science Technology Engineering and Math (STEM) Scholarship

July 2018

Awarded by Organization of Black Aerospace Professionals

#### **Induction to the King Club**

2015

Virgin Islands Chapter Tuskegee Airmen, Inc.

#### Robert J. Phipps Aviator Pioneer Club Award

2015

Virgin Islands Chapter Tuskegee Airmen, Inc.

#### Certifications and Licenses

#### CPR, AED, and First Aid Certified

June 2017 to June 2019

Certified to perform CPR, AED, and First Aid procedures on adult, children, and infants.

#### **Responsive Web Design**

August 2018 to Present

Completed freeCodeCamp's Responsive Web Design Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap 4.

#### **Full Stack JavaScript Techdegree**

January 2019 to Present

Enrolled in online degree which consist of 10 projects that focus on various programming technologies, such as: JavaScript, Node, React, Express, SQL.

#### Assessments

#### Critical Thinking — Expert

May 2019

Using logic to solve problems.

Full results: Expert

## **English Communication Skills: Typing — Expert**

May 2019

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard

Full results: Expert

## **Basic Computer Skills: PC — Expert**

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to perform basic computer operations, navigate a Windows OS, and troubleshoot common computer problems.

Full results: Expert

## Email — Expert

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to effectively compose and organize email messages.

Full results: Expert

#### **Social Media — Highly Proficient**

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to create content, communicate online, and build a brand's reputation.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### **Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient**

May 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Highly Proficient

## **Search Engine Optimization — Expert**

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to interpret online website performance metrics and understand search engine optimization tactics.

Full results: Expert

#### **Problem Solving — Expert**

May 2019

Analyzing relevant information when solving problems.

Full results: Expert

## Intermediate Word Processing with Microsoft Word — Expert

May 2019

Intermediate Word techniques, including the use of formatting, Track Changes, and Comments.

Full results: Expert

## Advanced attention to detail — Expert

August 2021

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information

Full results: Expert

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

## Groups

## Virgin Islands Chapter Tuskegee Airmen Club, Inc. Youth Aviation Club

November 2009 to Present

#### **American Red Cross - Virgin Islands Chapter**

September 2009 to Present

## **Boy Scouts Aviation Explorers**

February 2014 to Present

## **Organization of Black Aerospace Professionals**

April 2013 to Present

## **United States Coast Guard Auxiliary**

February 2016 to August 2018